Carlos Colmenares A.

Project Engineer

I have been a consultant for the development of highly technical IT projects in more than forty (40) national and foreign corporations and companies, some as prestigious as The Registro Nacional of Costa Rica (San José, Costa Rica), Banco Invercrédito (Bogotá, Colombia), and in Venezuela: PDVSA, CARGILL, as well as thirteen (13) banks. For the past twenty years, I have also been developed a successful career as a project engineer, especially in designing and installing electronic systems for public safety and microwave telecommunications



...My other passion has always been software programming, and as a freelancer, I develop professional websites, smartphones, and server applications. This passion forces me to stay constantly updated on new technologies and trends within the software development ecosystem.

Contact

+58 414 324 63 96

ccolmenaresa@gmail.com

https://carlos-colmenares-a.netlify.app

https://www.linkedin.com/cycscarlos

https://github.com/cycscarlos

Caracas, Estado Miranda, Venezuela

Education

1976-1981

Ingeniero Electrónico (Mención Telecomunicaciones)

Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnico Antonio José de Sucre

Skills

Web Development Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Python

NodeJS

My SQL

MongoDB

Figma

Licenses & certifications

1979-2023

IBM - s/370 Conceptos y Facilidades

BND - Organización y Metodos

IBM - OS/VS1 Conceptos y Facilidades

IBM - DOS/VSE Control de Sistema

IBM - DOS/VSE Conceptos y Facilidades

IBM - Codificación VSAM (COBOL)

IBM - Utilización VM/CMS

APIs

Artificial Intelligence

Mainframe skills

Assembler

Cobol ANSI 74

VSE, VM & zOS

CICS/ESA

ACF/VTAM & NCP

IBM - VM/SP Instalación

Banco Maracaibo - PERT C.P.M.

IBM - CICS/VS Codificación Nivel Comando

IBM - PL/1 Análisis de Aplicaciones

Abaco - THE LIBRARIAN

Abaco - ADR/DATADICTIONARY Utilización

The technical English Workshop - English

ADR (USA) - SQL for DB2 & ISA for DB2

IBM - SNA Data Flow & Performance

IBM - Capacity Planning

IBM - MVS/JCL Utilities

Computer Associates (USA) - CICS/VSE Internals

Computer Associates (USA) - CA-DISPATCH

Internals

Computer Associates (USA) - ACF/VTAM internals

Computer Associates (USA) - ACF/VTAM

Performance

IBM - Moving to VSE/ESA Client/Server Solutions

Conferences

1986 to 1988

IDEAS (Intercambio de Ideas Anuales de Software)

Hotel Caracas Hilton, Venezuela

Ponente | Temáticas:

- Performance & Tuning Aspects on VSE/ESA
- Virtual Machine (VM/SP) installation Topics
- Capacity Planning techniques on MVS/ESA

1988

System Software Conference

New Jersey, USA

Oyente

Work Experience

1977-1981

System Programmer Junior Banco Nacional de Descuento

"I was part of the team of specialists in the technical support division of the computing vice-presidency at the Bank. Like my colleagues, we were in charge of keeping the computational infrastructure based on IBM Mainframe technology operational"

1982-1984

System Programmer Senior Banco Maracaibo

"I was in charge of the team of specialists in the technical support division of the computing vice-presidency at the Bank. 1989

CADRE

New Jersey, USA

Oyente

2004

La Red del Estado

UNEFA, Venezuela

Oyente

2006

Gobierno Electrónico

UNEFA, Venezuela

Oyente

2006

Tecnología y Gerencia

IESA, Venezuela

Oyente

2011

Liderazgo y Transformación

IESA, Venezuela

Oyente

Hobbies

Basketball | Baseball | Boxing | Football | Music | Beach | Reading | die-hard technologist

Among other functions, I was responsible for maintaining the operational status of the computational infrastructure based on IBM Mainframe technology.

..and finally, coordinate with other IT areas for the implementation of new projects, research, testing, and production installation (DevOps) of new versions of operating systems or software packages for both systems and applications"

1984-1991

System Software Technical Director Sistemas de Computación ABACO

"I was in charge of the technical area for system software products of Computer Associates, Inc., a world leader in software development for IBM MVS, VM, and VSE operating systems. My main objective was to provide consulting and product installation services for clients with IBM Mainframe technology. The quality of the service provided and the projects success were endorsed by my hiring by foreign entities (such as Banco Invercrédito in Bogota, Colombia, and the National Registry of Costa Rica)"

1991-2011

Senior Project Engineer CYCS Computing specialist

"My goal was to develop and promote specialized consulting services management in two areas: 1. Capitalize on the highly technical requirements of those clients with IT infrastructure based solely on IBM Mainframe technologies, and design and installation of Microwave Telecommunications Networks and Industrial-grade Electronic Security Systems.

The success of my management is endorsed by the extensive hiring of clients for the development of high-level technical projects"

2012-2019

Senior Project Engineer CYCS Ingeniería e Instalaciones

"My goal was to develop and promote the new consulting area, focused on providing design, installation, and training services for telecommunications systems (specifically Microwave networks), and industrial-grade electronic security systems. The success of my management is endorsed, both by the quantity and the technical complexity of the projects contracted and successfully executed for large-scale and high-level corporate clients.

Below you will find links to two successful projects that were reviewed at the time by the Taiwanese company Airlive, a world leader in network technology and security video cameras"

CEGASA 2016. IP Video Surveillance and Telecommunication

FITVEN 2013. IP Video Surveillance and Telecommunication

2019 - Present

Senior Consultant Freelance

"During the pandemic phases (virus outbreak, lockdown, and the difficult post-pandemic era), I had to reinvent myself, and since then I provide services in the software engineering area of design and development of applications for smartphones, PCs, and servers. Likewise, I continue to provide maintenance services for legacy projects and the installation of new projects for clients in the areas of telecommunications and electronic security systems"